So it's for 11 people...
아홉, 열, 열하나
It's been so long since I made a portion this large.
음식을 이렇게 많이 해보긴 처음이야
Kasane, do you usually cook?
카사네 너 요리 잘해?
Not really.
잘 못해…
But Yuito sometimes does.
유이토는 가끔 하는 것 같아요
The steel bowl should be right here.
큰 그릇이 이쯤 있었던 것 같은데
How do you know?
그걸 어떻게 알아?
The shelters for Sumeragis
스메라기의 피난처는
are all the same.
전부 다 비슷하니까
Let me whisk the eggs for you.
계란은 나한테 맡겨
Really? I'll leave that to you.
진짜? 그럼 잘 부탁해
Mother.
엄마
I never thought I could spend quiet time like this with you.
너랑 이렇게 지내는 날이 올 줄이야
SCARLET NEXUS
"스칼렛넥서"
♫Felling of tiredness is losing yourself♫
나른해 losing yourself
♫How do you still create a relationship each other♫
관계를 이룰 방법을 못 찾은 건가
♫It’s my awkward friend’s fault♫
귀찮은 친구가 있어
♫Until death, wanting someone somewhere to embrace me♫
죽을 때까지 누군가의 포옹을 원해
♫While the devil is not here and between the chaos♫
겨우 숨 돌리는 혼돈과 허무함 속에
♫Aiming between win and lose♫
승리와 실패 사이에 목표를 둬
♫Not to be running out of patience for now, I’m trying to be careful♫
믿음을 벼랑 끝으로 몰지 마 조심해
♫You’ll see I’m always on your side♫
You'll see I'm always on your side
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
오늘도 죽을힘을 다해 연락해
♫You’re frigid and your roller coaster inside the brain♫
네 머릿속 차가운 궤도에 말이야
♫The grungy days and the unprecedented catastrophy♫
흔들었던 날들에는 없는 재난
♫Where is the glory buried?♫
영광은 어딘가에 묻어둔 지 오래
♫The lonely monster in a moment♫
이 순간 외로운 야수가
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
날아드는 탄알과 함께
♫To pierce with the theory♫
세상의 모든 이치를 꿰뚫어
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
오늘도 죽을힘을 다해 연락해
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
날아드는 탄알과 함께
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
오늘도 여전히 함께해 똑똑히 연락해
♫You’re frigid and the theory in the brain♫
네 머릿속 차가운 정의에 말이야
WAKANA'S RESOLVE
(와카나의 결심)
Good morning, Yuito.
굿모닝, 유이토
Good morning.
굿모닝
Are you feeling better now?
몸은 좀 괜찮아?
Much better now.
괜찮아
Shouldn't you take a break?
엄마야말로 무리하는거 아니지?
Time travel will exert a great amount of strain on the brain.
타임 점프 때문에 뇌에 부담이 클 텐데
I'm fine. Thank you for your concern.
난 괜찮아, 걱정해줘서 고맙네
I heard a lot of things from Kasane.
카사네가 참 많은 일들을 얘기해줬어
After comparing the data sent by BABE,
베이브가 나한테 전송한 자료와 비교해서
I've learned much about the situation.
많은 일들을 알게 되었어
And about Karen...
그리고 카렌의 일도…
Powers can be very handy for things like this.
초뇌능력이 이럴 때는 진짜 편하다니까
Well done, Yuito.
엄청 잘하네, 유이토
I actually like cooking.
내가 요리를 좀 좋아해서
I can even do this.
이렇게 할 수도 있어
Impressive.
대단한걸
I'll do the laundry.
난 세탁하러 갈게
Kasane...
카사네
It's all right.
괜찮아
-Mother, see you at dinner. -Sure.
-엄마, 이따 봐 -응
Mom, you need to take a break.
엄마, 앉아서 쉬고 있어
Thanks, but I'll be fine.
고마워, 하지만 괜찮아
You're becoming more like your father.
너 점점 더 아빠를 닮아가는 것 같아
No way. Brother is more like him.
형이 나보다 더 닮았는데 뭘
People always say I don't look like my father.
다들 내가 아빠를 안 닮았다고 해
I don't mean the look. It's the aura.
생김새가 아니라 느낌 말이야
How is Kaito lately?
카이토는 요즘 어때?
Are you two getting along?
둘은 서로 잘 지내고?
He is fine. But I wouldn't say we are getting along.
형은 잘 지내는데 우리 사이가 별로야
I see.
그렇구나
Yuito, about your father...
유이토, 네 아빠는 말이야
He saved me when Togetsu was hunting me down.
토게츠에 쫓기고 있던 나를 구해줬어
He was a kind person.
다정한 사람이야
As for Kaito, he's always wanted to be a politician
카이토는 이 나라를 바꾸기 위해
so he could change this country.
어려서부터 정치가가 되기로 결심했어
But he and I...
하지만 나랑 형은
It's all right.
괜찮아
You two are both our children.
너희 모두 엄마아빠의 아이들이잖아
Good morning.
좋은 아침이에요
Thank you for the food.
잘 먹겠습니다
By the way,
그나저나
why is Wakana being sent back to her timeline?
와카나 누님은 왜 원래 시대로 보내지지 않는 거예요?
I am not particularly strong, but I am still a wielder of the Red Strings.
약하긴 해도 나 역시 레드 스트링스 뇌능력자니까
But we can't afford to get too careless, right?
하지만 너무 방심하면 안되지?
Yes.
맞아
If we don't eliminate the dimension entanglement inside the Kunad Gate,
쿠나도 게이트 내부에 얽힌 차원을 없애지 않으면
the world will be destroyed very soon.
세상은 곧 멸망할 거야
Dimension entanglement?
얽힌 차원이요?
It's the traces of time manipulation.
시간을 간섭하는 흔적 말이야
The Kunad Gate is a dimensional portal formed during time travel.
쿠나도 게이트는 타임 점프할 때 임시적으로 생산되는 차원의 문이야
And because it resonates with Yuito and Kasane's power,
유이토와 카사네의 힘이 공명을 일으키는 이유로
it's been existing as a distorted form.
비뚤어진 채 계속 존재하는 거지
Yuito from the future said the same thing.
50년 뒤의 유이토도 그런 말을 했었어
A time travel via the distorted dimension
비뚤어진 공간을 통해 타임 점프하면
will create dimensional entanglement.
차원이 얽히게 돼
Undoing the dimensional entanglement will eliminate the Kunad Gate.
얽힌 차원을 풀어야만 쿠나도 게이트를 닫을 수 있어
What should we do?
우리가 뭘 해야 해?
Yuito, Kasane,
유이토, 카사네
you must both enter the Kunad Gate.
두 사람이 반드시 함께 쿠나도 게이트에 들어가야 해
Its inside is a conceptual space where only users of Red Strings exist subjectively.
그 안에는 레드 스트링스 뇌능력자의 주관이 존재하는 개념 공간이야
Is it the space with a lot of weird images?
기괴한 영상이 엄청 많이 존재하는 공간 말이야?
Yes.
맞아
Togetsu called it the Chronos Terminal.
토게츠에서는 크로노스 터미널이라고 불러
Chronos Terminal...
크로노스 터미널…
A terminal of time flow.
시간이 흐르는 정거장
Does it mean that's where timelines diverge?
소위 분기점이라고 하는 그건가요?
It's a space only Yuito and Kasane can understand.
유이토와 카사네만 이해할 수 있는 공간이군요
That must be why we didn't notice it even though we went to the future.
어쩐지 우리도 미래에 가서 발견했어요
Even without traveling to that timeline,
그 시대에 가지 않고
a slight touch from the existence of the Red Strings users
레드 스트링스 뇌능력자의 존재가 조금만 건드려도
will create entanglement.
그건 얽힐 수 있어
As for which timelines created the entanglement,
대체 어느 시대에서 얽히는 건지
you must search for them yourselves.
반드시 두 사람이 직접 확인해야 해
In the end, we still have to rely on Yuito and Kasane.
그럼 결국 유이토와 카사네한테 부탁할 수 밖에 없군
But after using the Red Strings...
하지만 레드 스트링스를 사용하면 또…
Yuito, don't overdo it.
유이토, 너무 무리하지 마
Yes.
응
Very well, let's go.
그럼 가볼까?
Mother, we'll be leaving now.
엄마, 가
What is it?
왜 그래?
Kasane, you grew up to become a great person.
카사네가 좋은 아이여서
I'm so proud of you.
참 다행이야
Well, I have no right to say that.
하지만 나도 그런 말 할 자격이 없어
After all, I once abandoned you.
내가 널 버리고 도망갔으니까
I'm so sorry.
정말 미안해
You don't have to apologize.
엄마가 왜 사과를 해
You almost lost your life back then.
엄마도 죽을뻔 했잖아…
I don't really remember what happened in Togetsu either.
그리고 나도 토게츠의 일이 기억나지 않아
Not to mention...
게다가…
I had Naomi to keep my company after I came to Suoh.
스오에 온 뒤로 나오미 언니가 곁에 있어줬어
I should really thank her for that.
그럼 나오미한테 감사 인사를 해야겠어
To think you still consider me your mother...
여전히 나를 엄마라고 불러주네…
-Let's go. -Yes.
-같이 가, 엄마 -응
The dimensional entanglement is like red threads that are entangled.
뒤얽힌 차원은 엉킨 레드 스트링스와 같아
You know how to undo the knots.
차원을 어떻게 풀어나갈지 너희들은 알 거야
Come back immediately if it gets too risky.
위험한 것 같으면 바로 돌아와
Yes.
응
As for my mother...
엄마를 부탁해…
Don't worry, you can count on us.
걱정 마, 안심해도 돼
We will keep Wakana safe.
와카나 누님을 잘 보호하고 있을게
-Thank you. -You have my thanks.
-고마워
Now, are you ready?
자, 두분 준비 되셨나요?
-Kasane, are you ready? -Yes.
-카사네, 괜찮겠어? -응
You must stay focused.
둘 다 정신을 집중하고
Imagine the view of Chronos Terminal.
크로노스 터미널을 떠올려 봐
Chronos Terminal...
크로노스 터미널
I will undo the dimensional entanglement.
반드시 얽힌 차원을 해결할 거야
-I think we made it. -Yeah.
-도착한 것 같아 -그래
Yuito, Kasane, over here.
유이토, 카사네, 여기야
Mother?
엄마?
Can you see it?
보여?
There are entanglement spots up ahead.
저기 앞에 얽혀있는 것들
Thank you, Mother.
고마워, 엄마
Leave the rest to us.
나머지는 우리한테 맡겨
Yes. Be careful.
그래, 조심해
Is this it?
이건가?
We just need to undo this entanglement from different timelines.
각각의 시대에 들어가서 얽힌 실타래를 풀면 되는 거지?
Let's start with this.
일단 여기부터
It's the old OSF hospital from the other day.
구 토벌군병원에 있었던 그날이야
Is this the inside of dimensional entanglement?
뒤얽힌 차원 속에 들어온 건가?
-Let's use the Red Strings. -Yes. That should undo this thing.
-레드 스트링스를 이용하면 -맞아, 풀 수 있을 것 같아
It's not separating.
따로 따로 풀 수는 없나 봐
We need to do it together.
함께 풀어야 해
Concentrate and continue.
집중해서 계속하자
Yes.
응
Take care of that line.
이건 네가 해
All right.
좋아
Let's keep it going.
계속해
We can do this.
가능할 것 같아
Not bad, Kasane. You're the older sister I can count on.
역시 카사네, 누나는 다르네
What do you mean?
뭔 뜻이야?
But you were born first.
네가 먼저 태어났잖아
We're of the same age.
그래도 우리 동갑이야
Kyoka said it was because of your cryosleep.
쿄카 말로는 냉동 수면을 했었다던데
But I must thank you.
그나저나 진짜 너한테 고마워
For what?
뭐가?
You saved me that day.
그날 나를 구해줘서 고마워
I haven't thanked you yet.
너한테 고맙단 인사도 제대로 못했네
Why are you bringing this up now?
갑자기 왜 인사를 해
That was the day I started using my power.
그때부터 힘을 쓸 수 있었거든
Maybe I got a tiny portion of power from you too.
어쩌면 네가 나에게 힘을 나눠준 걸지도 몰라
Brain power cannot be shared.
초뇌능력은 나눌 수 없는 거야
I know.
알아
However...
하지만…
I'm only alive now because we met that day.
그날 우리가 만났기 때문에 내가 이렇게 살 수 있는 거야
That's when I decided to join OSF.
토벌군이 되겠다는 목표도 생겼고
Kasane, thank you.
그러니까 고마워, 카사네
Thank you for saving me.
구해줘서 고마워
This is when I say
이럴 때는
you're welcome. Am I right?
괜찮다고 해야겠지?
Now, this is the last thread.
자, 이제 마지막 한가닥이야
-Our next target... -Suoh, 50 years from now.
-다음은 -50년 뒤의 스오야
It's the entanglement created when I met the future you.
미래의 너를 만나면서 얽힌 거야
This is Suoh 50 years into the future?
여기라고 50년 뒤의 스오라고?
Come, I know where it is.
따라와, 어디인지 내가 알아
Yuito.
유이토
What if you could rewrite history?
역사를 바꿀 수 있으면 좋겠다는 생각 해본 적 있어?
Do you mean by time travel?
타임 점프를 통해 과거로 넘어가는 거 말이야?
Wouldn't that create a new dimensional entanglement?
그럼 또 새로 얽힌 차원이 생산되잖아
I mean after the Kunad Gate is destroyed.
쿠나도 게이트가 사라진 뒤에 말이야
What if you could travel to any timeline you wanted?
만약 어느 시대든 마음대로 다닐 수 있다면?
I thought about it.
생각해본 적은 있어
I wish I had done it long ago.
그때 이렇게 했으면 좋았을 걸 하고 후회했었어
Yuito.
유이토
Since I'm dying anyway,
어차피 죽게 될 거…
What should I do?
나…어떻게 하면 좋을까…
I couldn't answer Nagi's question.
그때 나기의 말에 아무 대답도 못했어
Will you use the Red Strings to go back in time?
그럼 레드 스트링스를 이용해 과거로 돌아가고 싶어?
No.
아니
Even if I change the past,
과거를 바꾼다고 해도
the future is still full of uncertainties.
미래는 여전히 미지수이니까
If Nagi hadn't become my friend,
그리고 나기가 나랑 친구가 되지 않았다면
maybe he wouldn't have gotten caught up in all of this.
이렇게 나 때문에 얽힐 일도 없었을 거야
If I had never met Nagi,
내가 나기랑 만나지 않았다면
we wouldn't pursue the same dream.
함께 꿈 꾸는 일도 없었을 거야
To change the past over that
이것 때문에 과거를 바꾸는 건
is just not right.
옳지 않다고 생각해
Nagi deserves to have his own future.
나기도 자신만의 미래가 있는 건데
Just like the entanglement, nothing is absolute.
얽힌 차원과 마찬가지로 정확하다고 할 수는 없지
Changing another person's life based on my opinion
나 혼자만의 생각 때문에 다른 사람의 인생을 바꾸는 건
is just not right.
옳지 않다고 봐
I'm sorry for asking that strange question.
미안, 내가 이상한 질문을 했어
But I'm surprised.
그나저나 놀라워
I was thinking about the same thing.
나도 같은 생각이었거든
In the past, I might have given a different answer.
예전의 나라면 다른 답을 말했겠지만
I've had a different view of the world after meeting everyone.
모두와 함께 하면서 세계관이 바뀌었어
I understand. It was the same for me.
이해해, 나도 그랬거든
We share quite a lot in common, actually.
우리 꽤 잘 어울리네
Don't get ahead of yourself.
거기까지 생각하긴 이르지 않아?
Sorry...
미안…
This is it.
역시 여기구나
We'll start from the right side.
오른쪽부터 해결하자
Yes.
응
Kasane, are you all right?
카사네, 괜찮아?
Sorry. I'm fine.
미안, 나 괜찮아
Very well. Now, the left side.
자, 이제 왼쪽 차례야
Yes.
그래
Kasane, you can do it. Just a little more!
카사네, 힘내, 곧 끝나
I'll support that thread.
이건 내가 버틸 테니까
That's the last one.
저기 남은 것만 해
Kasane!
카사네
I'm fine.
난 괜찮아
Just one entanglement left.
이제 하나 남았어
Yes.
그래
Is that...
저건…
The crest of Sumeragi!
스메라기 문양인데
That's what I saw when I first came in here!
내가 여기 처음 왔을 때 봤었던 영상이야
Just as Mother said,
엄마가 말한 것과 같아
Another entanglement was created
뇌능력자를 건드린 우리가
when we came into contact with another power user.
뒤얽힌 차원을 만들어낸 거야
It's Karen!
카렌
What's going on?
무슨 일이 있었던 거지?
I don't know.
몰라
But this is going to get worse.
하지만 이러다가 더 심각해질 거야
-Let's do this. -Yes.
-시작하자 -그래
Not now! It's the overexertion of brain power...
하필 이때… 뇌능력을 너무 많이 사용했나…
No, we need to be faster.
큰 일이야, 얼른 시작하자
Did we make it?
성공했나…
Yuito, Kasane.
유이토, 카사네
Are we back?
우리 돌아온 거야?
You've both safe. Thank goodness.
다들 괜찮아? 다행이야
Yeah, we somehow made it.
겨우 돌아왔네
Is the Kunad Gate...
이제 쿠나도 게이트는…
Why is it still here?
왜 아직도 사라지지 않은거야?
You did well.
수고했어
You both did great.
둘 다 많이 애썼어
It's all right now.
이제 괜찮아
But...
하지만…
Mother, we undo the entanglements.
엄마, 우리가 뒤얽힌 차원을 풀었는데
But why...
왜 아직도…
Leave the rest to me.
이제부터는 나한테 맡겨
Mother...
엄마
You've made a lot of friends.
너희들 참 좋은 친구들을 만났어
This friendship is more precious than any Red String.
너희 사이의 감정이 레드 스트링스보다 더 훌륭한 거야
Cherish it.
꼭 잘 간직해
Thank you. You've become so strong.
잘 커줘서 진짜 너무 고마워
Mom, are you going back now?
엄마, 이제 과거로 돌아가려는 거야?
If you do, Togetsu...
돌아가면 토게츠에서…
It must be done.
이건 필연이야
Sorry, but staying here with you
미안하지만 난 이제 너희와 함께 할 수 없어
just doesn't seem right to me.
많이 불편할 거야
Wait! I still have so much to tell you!
잠깐만, 나 아직 하고 싶은 얘기가 많아
Mother...
엄마
Yuito, Kasane...
유이토, 카사네
May you have a happy life in the future.
행복한 미래에서 잘 살아가길 바래
-Mother! -Mom!
-엄마
Another entanglement was created when you traveled through time.
엄마가 타임 점프하면서 뒤얽힌 차원을 만들어냈어?
How did it happen?
어떻게 이럴 수가
As long as I stay, the Kunad Gate will continue to exist.
계속 여기에 남아있는 한 쿠나도 게이트는 사라지지 않는다고
That was what she said.
말하셨어
She left a message.
메세지를 남기셨어
Yuito, Kasane.
유이토, 카사네
I'm sorry this is how I bid you farewell.
이런 방식으로 이별해서 미안해
I should have told you in person.
내가 직접 말해줘야 하는 건데
But I don't think I'll be calm enough to explain everything to you.
너희들 앞에서 침착하게 말할 자신이 없었어
I must return to my own timeline.
난 내가 있었던 시대로 돌아갈 거야
No, I'll already be there.
아니, 이미 돌아갔다고 해야 맞지
I've made up my mind when I received the data from BABE.
베이브의 자료를 받고나서 결정한 거야
I must fulfill my duty
난 반드시 내 시대에 존재해야 해
in my own timeline.
내 인생에 책임져야 하거든
I could receive the data from Togetsu
내가 토게츠에서 보내온 자료를 받아들인 건
because they retrieved my brain.
토게츠에서 뇌를 회수했고
A connection was formed between BABE and me.
베이브와 연결되었기 때문이야
This outcome will surely make you sad.
분명 너희들이 힘들어할게 뻔하잖아
But I feel so happy.
그래도 너무 기뻐
I now know my two beloved children
내게 소중한 두 아이가
have grown up to become so strong and amazing.
어른이 된 모습을 볼 수 있어서 말이야
You can have my brain,
너희들한테 뇌를 넘겨줘도
but you cannot take away my memory of the future.
미래에 대한 기억은 절대 넘기지 않아
I'm sure the two of you can overcome anything.
앞으로 너희가 어떤 상황에 부딪혀도 잘 해결할 수 있을 거라 믿어
I'm grateful that you've come into this world.
태어나줘서 고맙고
Thank you for being alive
잘 살아남아줘서
and bringing my happiness.
또 내게 행복을 가져다줘서 고마워
Kaito.
카이토
Yuito.
유이토
Kasane.
카사네
Jo.
조…
WARNING, EXECUTING
(위험, 실행 중)
DELETION COMPLETE
(삭제 완료)
I hope the happiness you will have
두 사람이 내가 얻은 것의
is so much more than what I received.
몇배로 행복하길 바래
Yuito, Kasane.
유이토, 카사네
I love you.
사랑하는 내 아이들
PLAYBACK ENDED
(재생 완료)
♫I'm troubled by my own yearning♫
추구하는 동경에 사로잡혀
♫Unveil the blocked sun ray♫
아른거리며 앞을 막는 햇볕을 제껴
♫There's a stranger in me♫
There's a stranger in me
♫That I've never seen♫
여태 본 적이 없어
♫I can not soar in the sky without fear♫
공포는 묻어두고 하늘 높이 날 수 있을까
♫I'm spreading my wings♫
I'm spreading my wings
♫Dancing gracefully like a bird♫
예쁘게 춤추는 새들과
♫And gazing towards the scarlet sky♫
빨갛게 물든 하늘을 쳐다봐
♫I chased after the gust♫
강한 바람을 따라가
♫The scenery spreads into the ever-changing world♫
변해가는 세계에 경치가 퍼지고 있어
♫Inside the intertwined brilliance♫
뒤얽힌 빛 속에서
♫I'm still searching for tomorrow's direction♫
계속해 내일 걸어갈 길을 찾아
♫Tomorrow's in your hands♫
Tomorrow's in your hands
♫Don't tell me now you're afraid♫
Don't tell me now you're afraid
♫There's no time to waste♫
There's no time to waste
♫Go forward♫
나아가
♫Have no fear for anything♫
더 이상 아무것도 두려워하지 마
♫Now, let's go♫
함께 가
♫Into a brand new day♫
Into a brand new day
THE TWO BROTHERS
(형과 동생)